Unnikrishnan Thekkekuruvath

Technical Product Manager



About me

Hi, My name is Unni and currently a Technical Product Manager in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelvefactor app methodology, designing event-driven architecture and implementing infrastructure solutions and services, experienced in leading an engineering team to achive concrete goals on a strict deadline.

Grew up Quardrilingual (English, Malayalam, Hindi, Tamil).

Skills



Contact





+44 7561 105 147

unnithekkekuruvath

Experience

Technical Product Manager, Enterprise Engineering

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | since May 2019

- Managing Goal based pipeline and Application Authorisation Management Product team.
- Automated the process of onboarding users to CI/CD tools and technologies which reduced lead time from 48 hours to 5 mins.
- Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design.
- Actively involved in decision making of system design and architecture improvements by collaborating closely with customers/SMEs.
- Mentored junior engineers and continuously building best practices within the bank.

Lead Engineer, Enterprise Engineering

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Jan 2018 - May 2019

Managing engineering team in Edinburgh.

Head of Midrange

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Jun 2017 - Jan 2018

 Managing entire Midrange server estate (Tandem Server, OpenVMS, Unix Server).

Head of Unix KSOR

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Oct 2014 - Jun 2017

Managing support of Unix Servers across the bank.

Unix Team Lead

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

Managing support of Unix Servers across the bank.

Senior Unix System Administrator

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Nov 2005 - Oct 2010

· Working as System admin looking after Sun, HP, AIX and Linux Servers.

Senior Unix System Administrator

CSC, Edinburgh | Jun 2003 - Oct 2005

Working as System admin looking after Motorola account.

Senior Unix System Administrator

Motorola, Bathgate | Jul 1999 - Jun 2003

Working as System admin looking after Sun and AIX servers.

Unix System Administrator

BT, Milton Keynes | May 1998 - Jun 1999

· Working as System admin looking after Sun and AIX servers.

Technical Consultant

Ensign International BV, Amsterdam | Jul 1997 - Mar 1998

· Working as Consultant looking after Ensign Clients.

Developer

Pentafour, Chennai | Jul 1996 - Jul 1997

· Working as developer coding in GuptaSQL.



Education

Master of Business Administrator(MBA), Edinburgh Napier University 2012 - 2015